[Music]
welcome to this what's new it's actually
what's old key updates in our learning
content for system Architects and
integration developers wow that's a long
title but it's also a long agenda
we uh in this video I will show you some
new guidance or documentation around
Integrations to and from business
Central uh we'll go through an overview
and then we'll dive into M Microsoft 365
or office apps Power Platform Dynamics
products and dataverse end up with
integrating to Asher infrastructure
services and a little bit on web
services because that's act the
foundation for all of these
Integrations okay let's let's dive into
the integration overview this piece of
documentation or guidance is here for
you to understand how Integrations work
not necessarily why you would make such
an
integration uh because this part of the
of the documentation is for you as an
architect or developer to understand
first of all what's possible and also
how to troubleshoot this should you
encounter any issues with any of these
Integrations the diagram you see here is
business Central in the middle on the on
the bottom of that we have three classes
of services and products what we call
foundational Services we have Asher we
have foundational services such as as
Microsoft inra and Dynamics uh products
and data verse in the middle you see
these two Integrations to and from
business uh sorry um two and from mic
roft uh 365 or office apps and Power
Platform and both of these you can think
of ways to augment the outof thee boox
functionality in business Central with
with more so with all of these Services
you can simply do more with business
Central and and uh and these augmented
products and then on top of the diagram
you see things or apps that built on top
of of business Central connect apps is
where you integrate to apis Microsoft
apps think of this as out of the box
supplied apps uh to do integration to
Shopify and Banking and others and then
the full Suite of Microsoft app Source
apps um where you can install those and
integrate to anything you
like the integration overview I'll just
show you a snippet of that um with all
the different things I show you here
there's also um both the actual page but
also the on the table of content to your
to to to the left in the page also a way
to navigate to that content and uh
expand each of these uh topics so let's
dive in there's a new landing page
called
aka.ms slbc integration let's take a
look and uh see how how it
looks all right so using the new AKA
link I go to docs and here you can see
uh the new integration overview each of
the topics you see in the in the diagram
has their has it its
own uh section here so for instance if I
click here in this article integrating
to office apps and M Microsoft 365 I get
an overview of a quick overview of what
is possible including a link here if I
want to dive further in and that's the
kind of the structure of the overall
integration overview it gives you a
snippet information and you can dive
into more
details so let's quickly dive into
integrating to Microsoft 365 or office
apps here you see a diagram with
different arrows to and from business
Central that also indicates um whether
information is going to and from
business Central from these apps and
going into the overview article you can
see that we have integration to excel
words Outlook and so on uh both in
integr into into the overview article
and you can you can dive further
in if we talk about the other augment
class of services Power Platform most of
these integrate with uh with rest apis
using the Power Platform
connector um and uh that is is is
covered in depth both in the new article
overview article on power platform
integration and also linking to all the
different detailed documentation for
each of the Power Platform
products integrating with Dynamics
products uh and data verse can happen
both through the connector and also
through different various different data
integration methods and therefore uh it
comes with an overview article that
explain the four different type of
integration data synchronization data
Vis virtualization change events and uh
and the new business events so go there
and and check it out um if you want to
integrate with dataverse and also some
of the Dynamics Products that come with
the dataverse
integration business Central allows you
to integrate with a V variety of as
Services most of these um is through the
HP client data type in Al and then there
are various system modules that
encapsulate the aure apis so to make it
easier to connect to these
Services um so there are many different
types of Integrations application
insights is actually built in so this is
telemetry but we have aser blop Services
file Services aser functions and a few
more in there so in case you need to
integrate to an AER service it might be
that there's already support for that in
a system application module
infrastructure services or foundational
services this is where you see things
like Microsoft entra for authentication
authorization where you have Universal
print and upcoming also Microsoft
purview for audit uh purposes or audit
functionality so all of these also come
with the its own article and uh and
documentation so go check that out there
are probably a few things within AER no
sorry with within Microsoft intra that
could be of interest this is for
instance where you can restrict I mean
did you know that you can restrict
network access to and from business
Central using um a security service taxs
that also is part of of U um of
this and then finally we update the web
service documentation uh with a new
overview of that so my business Central
supports three
different ways to integrate to web
services rest apis which is what you
should use and then o data and soap uh
these Legacy ways to um enable web
services through pages queries and or
code units and this also has a fairly
decent update in documentation uh both
for security for troubleshooting
performance errors and so on so go check
that out or at least familiar familiar
familiarize yourself with the new
content so in case you would need to
troubleshoot anything uh you know what's
there so that's it there are some
Goos uh of course memorize the new AKA
link BC
integration uh basically whenever you
start something new try to go to docs
and start your learning uh we try to put
everything there so that you don't have
to go and look in on the internet on uh
on some obscure uh blocks maybe this is
already covered in the official
documentation and when it doubt about
how something works or how we can troot
I encourage you to go to docs I think
you might be uh you you might see that
it it's it's probably already explained
there what whatever issue you have and
if you if you're an expert on something
and you know this is not in docs then do
a a pull request and help others um um
by by making the the documentation
better and of course if there's
something completely missing uh let us
know and we'll work on adding that
content other sessions that might be of
relevant for you for developers um if in
case you're into Integrations maybe
you're you're also into web services so
there's a session for what's new in web
services and similarly for integration
there's actually a full um session on
what's new updates in documentation for
for core Al developers so if you
consider yourself uh a core Al developer
go check that session out as
well other relevant sessions here in the
ble for Integrations uh could be new uh
the new way to integrate to field
service there's a session on that um new
stuff on Power Platform a session on
that and uh the news uh the watch news
session on integrating with data verse
so go check that out as well as always
we have resources uh different AKA links
so for for questions on uh discussions
BC yamama is your friend BC all is the
AK link that TR try to uh give you all
the AKA links so one link to rule them
all uh BC ideas if you have ideas for
improvements in the product or features
um we have various social media so on X
there's a hashtag for BC uh Ms Dynamics
then d d 365 BC we are we active on
Twitter and sorry on on LinkedIn and uh
of course we have office hours B office
hours where you can both participate and
also you can see previous
recordings that's it thank you for
watching and have a great launch
event